The following content is provided
提供以下内容
under a Creative Commons license.
根据知识共享许可。
Your support will help MIT OpenCourseWare continue
您的支持将帮助MIT OpenCourseWare继续
to offer high quality educational resources for free.
免费提供高质量的教育资源。
To make a donation, or view additional materials
捐款或查看其他材料
from hundreds of MIT courses, visit MIT OpenCourseWare
从数百门麻省理工学院的课程中，访问MIT OpenCourseWare
at ocw.mit.edu.
在ocw.mit.edu。
PROFESSOR: So we're going to do a problem that
教授：所以我们要解决一个问题
looks like the guitar problem.
看起来像吉他问题。
But it's a bit cooler.
但这有点凉。
At the same time, there are fewer states,
同时，状态更少
so I think it's easier to manage.
所以我认为它更容易管理。
How many people know how to play DDR?
有多少人知道怎么玩DDR？
AUDIENCE: Well.
听众：嗯。
PROFESSOR: Yeah.
教授：是的。
OK.
好。
How many people know the rules of playing DDR?
有多少人知道玩DDR的规则？
Because otherwise I won't be able to lift my hand up.
因为否则我将无法举起我的手。
OK.
好。
OK, so let's go through an algorithmic model.
好的，让我们看一下算法模型。
So, you have a board that basically looks like this.
因此，您拥有一个基本上像这样的板。
And you have four touch sensitive pads.
您有四个触摸感应板。
Up, down, left, right.
上下左右。
And then you have a center position.
然后，您将处于中心位置。
You also have a sheet of notes that looks something like this.
您还会看到一张看起来像这样的笔记。
Say, up, up down, down, up down, up, up down, left right,
说，向上，向上，向下，向下，向上，向下，向上，向上，向下，向左，向右，
left, left right, right.
左，左，右，右。
So on and so forth.
等等等等。
So when you see an arrow of up, that's
因此，当您看到向上的箭头时，
a constraint that says one of your feet
说你一只脚的约束
has to be on the up arrow.
必须在向上箭头上。
Has to tap the up arrow, actually.
实际上必须点击向上箭头。
There's no constraint for the other foot.
另一只脚没有任何约束。
So your other foot can be anywhere else on the board.
因此，另一只脚可以放在板上的其他任何位置。
It doesn't matter.
没关系
You are also allowed to tap the board some extra times.
您也可以在某些额外时间轻按板子。
So if you don't have a note showing up,
因此，如果您没有出现注释，
you can still hit the board.
您仍然可以发挥作用。
And there's no penalty.
而且没有罚款。
So you can hop around as many times as you want,
这样您就可以随意跳很多次，
or as many times as you can, until you run out of breath.
或尽可能多的次数，直到您喘不过气来。
So up basically means, it's actually one foot has to be up.
因此，上升基本上意味着必须抬起一只脚。
The other one center.
另一个中心。
Also, of course, because of the design of the board,
而且，当然，由于主板的设计，
it doesn't matter what foot is where.
哪只脚在哪里都没关系。
So what are possible goals for this game?
那么这个游戏可能有什么目标呢？
AUDIENCE: Not to get an F.
听众：不要拿F。
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
AUDIENCE: Hit all the arrows when
听众：
they line up with the top row.
他们与第一行对齐。
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
So there are two different ways of doing it.
因此，有两种不同的实现方法。
One, you said, "not to get an F."
您说过一个，“不要拿F。”
So I would say, given some limited set of skills.
所以我要说的是，由于技能有限。
So given a set of skills, or your skill level
因此，给定一组技能或您的技能水平
maximizes your score. right?
最大化您的分数。对？
AUDIENCE: Yeah.
听众：是的。
PROFESSOR: This is dynamic programming,
教授：这是动态编程，
so we always want to maximize something.
所以我们一直想最大化某些东西。
Now, if you're really good, then another possible goal
现在，如果您真的很好，那么另一个可能的目标
is hit all the notes with a minimum amount of effort.
以最小的努力击中所有音符。
If you're going to be in a competition,
如果您要参加比赛，
and you're going to be doing 10 songs,
您将要制作10首歌曲，
you don't want to die after the first song, right?
你不想死于第一首歌，对吗？
So, assuming you can do everything reasonably well,
因此，假设您可以将所有事情做好，
this is another possible goal.
这是另一个可能的目标。
Any other goals?
还有其他目标吗？
So we're brainstorming here.
所以我们在这里集思广益。
This isn't set in stone.
这不是一成不变的。
We've already seen the formal solution for this problem.
我们已经看到了解决此问题的正式解决方案。
So I want to play with it for a little bit, right?
所以我想玩一点，对吗？
We brought a DDR pad, so I want to play with it.
我们带来了DDR垫，所以我想玩它。
What else could you hope to maximize or minimize
您还希望最大化或最小化什么
for with dynamic programming?
对于动态编程？
AUDIENCE: Not look ridiculous.
听众：看起来并不荒谬。
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
AUDIENCE: I guess we're looking at the cost of each move,
观众：我想我们正在考虑的是每一步的成本，
right?
对？
PROFESSOR: So, hit all the notes.
教授：所以，打所有音符。
Minimum effort, or otherwise say best appearance.
花费最少的精力，或者说是最好的外观。
So every move looks somewhat good or somewhat bad.
因此，每一步看起来都有些好坏。
And you want to do the moves that look as good as possible.
您想做的动作看起来尽可能的好。
So this maximizes entertainment, right?
因此，这可以最大程度地提高娱乐性，对吗？
if you're on TV, you probably want this.
如果您在电视上，则可能需要这样做。
Now suppose you are in a competition
现在假设您正在参加比赛
and you only have one track to play.
而且只有一首曲目可以播放。
AUDIENCE: Well, you know where all the notes are.
听众：好吧，你知道所有笔记在哪里。
PROFESSOR: Sure.
教授：当然可以。
Like, we assume that we know this ahead of time.
就像，我们假设我们提前知道这一点。
So you've memorized this.
所以你已经记住了。
And you're trying to compute the best strategy,
而且您正在尝试计算最佳策略，
so you can memorize that.
所以你可以记住。
Then when you go and play, you dominate.
然后，当您去玩时，您就占了上风。
AUDIENCE: Yeah.
听众：是的。
PROFESSOR: So, if you have one track,
教授：所以，如果您有一个曲目，
then I would say that what you'd want to do
那我想说的是你想做什么
is minimize your probability of failure.
使您的失败可能性降到最低。
Right?
对？
So given the probability of failure for each possible move.
因此，给定每个可能动作失败的可能性。
You want to minimize the overall probability of failure
您希望最大程度地减少失败的可能性
so your teammates won't hate you.
这样你的队友就不会讨厌你。
So, hit all the notes and minimize.
因此，点击所有音符并最小化。
So this one's a little bit different from the other ones
所以这个跟其他的有点不同
because all the other ones are already
因为其他所有的都已经
set up as a nice problem where you add up things.
设置为一个很好的问题，在其中添加东西。
So you can solve them with graphs
所以你可以用图来解决
or with dynamic programming.
或使用动态编程。
If you want to minimize the probability of failure,
如果您想最大程度地减少失败的可能性，
then you want to maximize the probability of success.
那么您想最大化成功的可能性。
The probability of succeeding on all your moves
您的所有举动成功的可能性
is the product of the probability
是概率的乘积
of succeeding on each move.
每一步成功的秘诀。
All right?
好吧？
So if you have five moves, then you
因此，如果您有五步动作，那么您
have five individual probabilities.
有五个个体概率。
You multiply them up.
你乘以它们。
And that's the probability that you execute the whole sequence
这就是您执行整个序列的可能性
correctly, and not stumble.
正确，而不是绊倒。
So we have products instead of sums.
所以我们有乘积而不是和。
Yes?
是？
AUDIENCE: Isn't it related to the maximizing score goal?
听众：这与最大化得分目标有关吗？
PROFESSOR: You can.
教授：可以。
Well, not necessarily because this one
好吧，不一定因为这个
says that you only have some possible moves.
说你只有一些可能的举动。
I think in the end, all of them, except for this last one,
最后，我认为所有这些人，除了最后一个，
can be solved using the recursion depth we have for it.
可以使用我们拥有的递归深度来解决。
The last one, you have to do a bit of massaging.
最后一个，您需要做一些按摩。
And we're going over that right now.
我们现在要解决这个问题。
So, you have products instead of sums.
因此，您需要乘积而不是总和。
How do you turn products into sums?
您如何将产品转化为总和？
AUDIENCE: Logs?
听众：原木？
PROFESSOR: Yep.
教授：是的。
So, for this one, I would want to use logs,
因此，对于这一点，我想使用日志，
so that I can say that I want to maximize
这样我可以说我想最大化
the log probability of success.
成功的对数概率。
Which is just the sum of the log probabilities for each move.
这只是每一步的对数概率之和。
And then it looks like dynamic programming, as usual.
然后像往常一样看起来像动态编程。
Now, if I wouldn't want to use logs,
现在，如果我不想使用日志，
if I'm using the DP formulation, where I'm doing recursion,
如果我使用DP公式进行递归，
I can incorporate products there.
我可以在这里合并产品。
But it turns out, I didn't practice.
事实证明，我没有练习。
If you have a lot of numbers that are close to 1,
如果您有很多接近1的数字
or that are close to 0, so all the easy moves
或接近0，所以所有容易的动作
are going to be really close to 1, for example.
例如，实际上将接近1。
If you have a lot of numbers that are close to 1 or close
如果您有很多数字接近1或接近
to 0, if you multiply them up, you
到0，如果将它们相乘，
get numerical instabilities.
得到数值不稳定性。
So we get the number that's really close to 1.
所以我们得到的数字实际上接近于1。
So for example, if I'm choosing whether to do, say I'm here,
例如，如果我要选择是否要说我在这里，
and I'm thinking, do I want to move like this?
我在想，我想这样走吗？
Or do I want to move like this, and then like this?
还是我想这样移动然后再这样移动？
These are both pretty easy moves.
这些都是很容易的举动。
So, in both cases, we're looking at probabilities
因此，在两种情况下，我们都在研究概率
of success of 99.991%.
成功率的99.991％。
And maybe 99.992%.
也许是99.992％。
So if you have numbers with probabilities
所以如果你有概率的数字
that are really close to 1, and if you have a lot of them
确实接近1，如果有很多
and you try to multiply them, you're
然后尝试将它们相乘
going to get a bad result.
会得到不好的结果。
So all the products are going to start looking the same.
因此，所有产品都将开始看起来相同。
So we're going to get a random solution,
因此，我们将获得一个随机的解决方案，
instead of what you want.
而不是你想要的。
This is a practical thing.
这是实际的事情。
It's called numerical instability.
这就是数值不稳定性。
And it's a practical reason why you'd
这是您为什么要这样做的实际原因
want to use logs, instead of multiplying things up.
想要使用日志，而不是事半功倍。
So it's not just a theoretical thing.
因此，这不仅仅是理论上的事情。
It also makes life nice in practice.
在实践中，这也使生活变得美好。
OK.
好。
So we have a goal that looks like this.
因此，我们的目标看起来像这样。
Say, let's go for this one.
说，让我们开始吧。
Hit all the notes, minimize the effort.
打所有的笔记，最大程度地减少工作量。
And all the other ones can be reduced to this one.
所有其他的都可以简化为这个。
We need to define effort, right?
我们需要定义努力，对吗？
Let's say that we have a function called delta, that
假设我们有一个叫做delta的函数
takes two foot locations-- so, where both of my feet
需要两个脚的位置-所以，我的两只脚
are-- from and to.
是-从和到。
And it gives me a number from 0 to 1, where 0 is really easy.
它给了我一个从0到1的数字，其中0真的很简单。
And 1 is really hard.
而且1真的很难。
So from would look something like, my left foot is up.
因此，从看起来像，我的左脚向上。
My right foot is centered.
我的右脚居中。
To would look something like, my left foot is centered
看起来像是我的左脚居中
and my right foot is up.
我的右脚抬起
So basically going from here to here.
所以基本上是从这里到这里。
So from left foot up.
所以从左脚向上。
Right foot center.
右脚中心。
To here.
到这里。
So there is some difficulty there, right?
所以那里有些困难，对吧？
We have to jump, so it's not 0.
我们必须跳，所以它不是0。
I'm burning some calories here.
我在这里燃烧一些卡路里。
So any move that I make has some difficulty.
因此，我的任何举动都会有些困难。
And I want to solve the game so that overall I
我想解决游戏问题，以便总的来说，
have a reasonably small total difficulty.
总难度相对较小。
OK, are we understanding the problem?
好，我们了解问题了吗？
So we have three possible avenues here.
因此，这里有三个可能的途径。
We can start solving it using dynamic programming.
我们可以开始使用动态编程来解决它。
We can start solving it using graphs.
我们可以开始使用图形来解决它。
Or we can have someone else play the DDR again so that we
或者我们可以让其他人再次玩DDR，以便我们
can get more hands on experience,
可以获得更多经验
and look at what a good strategy or a bad strategy looks like.
然后看一下好策略或坏策略的模样。
So you guys get to vote.
这样你们就可以投票了。
Who wants to solve this using the dynamic programming?
谁想使用动态编程解决这个问题？
Who wants to solve this using graphs?
谁想用图表解决这个问题？
Who wants to get more hands on experience?
谁想获得更多实践经验？
Damn.
该死的。
I was hoping that DDR would win.
我希望DDR能赢。
You guys are boring.
你们真无聊
So, graphs, right?
那么，图吧？
We're going to have notes.
我们将有笔记。
Notes represent states, right?
注释代表状态，对不对？
So a state is where you are at some point in the game.
因此，状态是您在游戏中处于某个位置的位置。
And we'll have to define what where you are means.
而且，我们必须定义您所在的位置。
And then, when you jump, you make a move.
然后，当您跳跃时，便采取了行动。
So moves go between states.
因此，在状态之间进行移动。
So in any game, you have states and moves.
因此，在任何游戏中，您都有状态和动作。
A state is very hard to put in time.
状态很难及时设定。
And then you make a move.
然后您采取行动。
Like in chess.
就像在国际象棋中一样。
Your state is your board position.
您的状态就是您的董事会职位。
And whether you're moving, or your opponent
不管你是移动还是对手
is the next to move.
是下一步行动。
And the move is when you take a piece and put it from one place
而移动就是当您从一块放到一块放到一块
to another.
到另一个。
So your vertices are states.
因此，您的顶点就是状态。
And your edges are moves.
和你的边缘是移动。
So what's in a state?
那么状态如何？
This is our problem.
这是我们的问题。
Whether we're solving it with graphs
是否用图来解决
or with dynamic programming, this
或通过动态编程，
is what everything comes down to.
就是一切。
What's in the state?
状态如何？
AUDIENCE: So your current state is how much difficulty
观众：所以您目前的状态是多少困难
have you-- what is the problem?
你有什么问题吗？
Are those representing the probabilities,
是代表概率的那些，
the difficulties?
困难？
Or.
要么。
PROFESSOR: So this is the difficulty for one move.
教授：这就是一举一动的困难。
Does it depend on previous moves?
是否取决于先前的举动？
AUDIENCE: No, but.
听众：不，但是。
PROFESSOR: No.
教授：不。
So it's a nice thing to note that the difficulties
因此，很高兴注意到困难
for each move are independent.
每个动作都是独立的。
AUDIENCE: Would it be dependent in real life?
听众：这会取决于现实生活吗？
You'll get tired at the end.
最后你会累的。
And he's able to have less energy.
而且他的能量更少。
PROFESSOR: Yep.
教授：是的。
So, in real life, we might want to say that this actually
因此，在现实生活中，我们可能想说
depends on how much energy you've expended so far.
取决于您到目前为止已消耗了多少能量。
And if we have time, let's solve that problem.
如果有时间，让我们解决这个问题。
So the nice thing about this problem
所以关于这个问题的好处
is there are many directions in which we can take it.
我们可以采取许多方向吗？
This is one of them.
这就是其中之一。
I'm fine.
我很好。
And I think we'll learn a lot by doing that.
我认为这样做会学到很多东西。
So back to the original problem.
回到原来的问题。
Suppose that it doesn't matter how tired you are.
假设你有多累都没关系。
You're pretty good, so you're not
你很好，所以你不是
going to be tired enough to go [GASP].
够累了[GASP]。
So, mostly independent difficulties for each move.
因此，每个动作大多都是独立的困难。
What's in a state?
什么状态？
AUDIENCE: The sum of the difficulties up to that point.
听众：到那时为止困难的总和。
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
So.
所以。
AUDIENCE: Your appearance factor,
听众：你的外表因素，
if we're including that.
如果我们包括在内。
Or are we only doing--
还是我们只是在做-
PROFESSOR: So we're doing this.
教授：所以我们正在这样做。
AUDIENCE: Oh, I was just.
听众：哦，我只是。
Oh, effort.
辛苦了
OK, we're minimizing effort.
好的，我们正在努力。
PROFESSOR: So the way I like to think of this
教授：所以我喜欢这样想
is, what is does a solution look like?
是，解决方案是什么样的？
It's made up of decisions, right?
它是由决定组成的，对不对？
What are the decisions?
有什么决定？
AUDIENCE: To make that move or don't make that move?
听众：要采取行动还是不采取行动？
PROFESSOR: We'll see.
教授：我们会看到的。
But once you know what the decisions are,
但是一旦知道了决定是什么，
then you have to think, what do I need to make a decision?
然后您必须考虑，我需要做出什么决定？
AUDIENCE: The note.
听众：笔记。
PROFESSOR: So, a note is one of these.
教授：因此，便笺就是其中之一。
For some reason, they're called notes.
由于某种原因，它们被称为便笺。
AUDIENCE: So you know that somehow you
听众：所以你以某种方式知道你
have to hit all of them?
必须打所有人？
Like, you can have steps in between.
就像，您可以在两者之间进行操作。
PROFESSOR: Yep.
教授：是的。
AUDIENCE: Moves in between.
听众：在两者之间移动。
You have to hit all of them.
您必须全部击中。
PROFESSOR: OK, so I like this.
教授：好的，所以我喜欢这个。
So, every one of these is going to have to generate a move.
因此，其中的每一个都将不得不采取行动。
And there might be some moves in between.
两者之间可能会有一些动作。
Well, each move is going to map to some edge.
好吧，每一步都将映射到某个边缘。
And I'm going to need vertices.
而且我将需要顶点。
So, as an algorithms program where when I hear that, oh.
所以，作为算法程序，当我听到时，哦。
I can have some moves in between, I get really uneasy.
我之间可以有一些动作，我真的很不安。
Like, what is this?
就像，这是什么？
How many moves am I going to have?
我要走几步？
Is this going to become really huge?
这会变得非常巨大吗？
And am I not going to be able to run any algorithm on it?
而且我将无法在其上运行任何算法吗？
So let's think about that.
因此，让我们考虑一下。
How many moves would I have in between?
我之间会有几步动作？
And, what would I achieve with them?
而且，我将与他们达成什么目标？
AUDIENCE: I guess you'd have a max of, like, four, right?
听众：我想您最多可以有四个，对吧？
I mean, you can put your right leg someplace,
我的意思是，您可以将右腿放在某个位置，
and you can put your left leg someplace.
你可以把你的左腿放在某个地方。
That's like a max of two.
最多只能有两个。
Right?
对？
Or no?
或者没有？
PROFESSOR: So, let's think of an example.
教授：那么，让我们考虑一个例子。
You want to go, say, I want to go, what?
你想去，说，我想去，什么？
From here to here, right?
从这里到这里，对吗？
AUDIENCE: Um-hmm.
听众：嗯。
PROFESSOR: And you're thinking what?
教授：那你在想什么？
They can do this, oh sorry.
他们可以这样做，抱歉。
So I can do this as one move.
因此，我可以一口气做到这一点。
And this is one move.
这是一招。
AUDIENCE: Yeah.
听众：是的。
Or you can just do one jump, right?
或者您也可以跳一跳，对吗？
So it's-- oh, yeah.
哦，是的。
I guess that's more than one.
我想那不止一个。
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
So looking at this, if I'm considering
所以看这个，如果我正在考虑
whether to go from here to here.
是否从这里到这里。
If I want to go either this way, or if I want to go this way.
如果我想这样走，或者我想这样走。
So let's write this down on the board.
因此，让我们将其写下来。
So I'm going from up down to left right.
所以我要从上到下从左到右。
And I'm considering, do I want to go directly
我正在考虑，我想直接去吗
or do I want to go up right first.
还是我想先上升。
And then left right.
然后从左向右。
Let's not do these arrows because they're confusing.
我们不要做这些箭头，因为它们很混乱。
So, do I want to transition like this?
那么，我要这样过渡吗？
Or do I want to transition like this?
还是我想这样过渡？
Well, I claim that, since my moves are independent,
好吧，我声称，由于我的举动是独立的，
going from here to here, if it's beneficial to go
从这里到这里，如果有益的话
this way instead of this way, I would
这样，而不是这样，我会
want to go this way all the time.
想一直走这种路。
So I would just say that, look.
所以，我只想说，看。
Inside my delta here, I would say that, actually,
在我的三角洲内，我会说，实际上，
if you know what you're doing, whenever you have
如果知道自己在做什么，只要有
to go from here to here, you're going to go like this.
从这里到这里，您将像这样去。
And the delta is going to report to the total delta for this.
增量将为此报告总增量。
So, if the problem is that they have one note,
因此，如果问题在于他们只有一张纸条，
and then I have my next note like this, between these two
然后我在这两个之间有下一个音符
notes, I can always go in one move.
笔记，我总是可以一move而就。
AUDIENCE: So you're saying 1 would
听众：所以你说1
like, including in our difficulty function,
包括我们的难度函数在内
it'll also tell us, like, what move
它也会告诉我们，例如什么动作
we should make to get there?
我们应该去那里吗？
PROFESSOR: How to get there.
教授：如何到达那里。
The best way to get from one state to another.
从一种状态到达另一种状态的最佳方法。
Well, like when you're learning DDR,
好吧，就像您在学习DDR一样，
these are the basic steps, right?
这些是基本步骤，对吧？
Like, you practice until you know how to get from one place
就像，你练习直到知道如何从一个地方去
to another.
到另一个。
There is something else where you need intermediate steps.
还有其他一些地方需要中间步骤。
AUDIENCE: Or if you're holding one
听众：或者如果您拿着一个
and then you've got to move to another.
然后您必须移至另一个。
Right?
对？
PROFESSOR: So, let's not worry about holds.
教授：所以，我们不用担心搁置。
Let's say that we would just represent
假设我们只是代表
holds as-- so if you have a hold in a game, then
保持为-因此，如果您在游戏中处于保持状态，则
we're just going to represent it like this.
我们只是要这样表示。
We're going to cheat.
我们要作弊。
So we don't have to deal with it.
因此，我们不必处理它。
In real life, you would have to deal with it.
在现实生活中，您将不得不处理它。
Like if you're actually writing a program that trains people.
就像您实际上在编写训练人员的程序一样。
AUDIENCE: What happens if you have, like, right, left, up
听众：如果您有左右，左上，左上的姿势会怎样
or something.
或者其他的东西。
So let's say you start off hitting your right foot
假设您开始打右脚
on the top, and then you have to hit the right one again.
在顶部，然后您必须再次点击正确的一个。
And then you have to hit up again
然后你必须再打一次
and then you have to transfer.
然后您必须转移。
So I guess anytime you have to through the middle.
所以我想您随时都需要经历中间阶段。
You have move your foot.
你已经动了脚。
PROFESSOR: So I like the idea of going through the middle.
教授：所以我喜欢经历中间的想法。
Why or how do you, why would you go through the middle?
你为什么或怎么样，为什么要经历中间？
AUDIENCE: To avoid crossing your leg over or something.
听众：为避免双腿交叉或其他东西。
PROFESSOR: Well, what if I have something like this?
教授：好吧，如果我有这样的事情怎么办？
If there are DDR experts, I know this isn't the right way
如果有DDR专家，我知道这不是正确的方法
to do it.
去做吧。
But one way of doing it is left, right, left, right, left,
但是一种方法是左，右，左，右，左，
right.
对。
So then, I have some states that account for the fact
因此，我有一些状态说明了这一事实
that I'm centering.
我正在居中。
So, some people like to do this, right?
所以，有些人喜欢这样做，对吗？
Some people like to go to the center as much as possible,
有些人喜欢尽可能地去中心，
if they have time between the moves.
如果他们在两次行动之间有时间。
So then, I would need at least one state
因此，我将需要至少一个状态
in between where I'm allowed to center, right?
在允许我居中的位置之间，对吗？
In order to represent what I just did there,
为了代表我刚才在那做的事，
I need one move.
我需要一招。
So, one way I could meet this is I have left center.
因此，我可以实现的一种方法是离开中心。
And then left right.
然后从左向右。
And then left right, left right, left right.
然后左右，左右，左右。
So on and so forth.
等等等等。
But this would mean that instead of doing this, which
但这意味着，而不是这样做，
is reasonably easy, I would have to do this.
是相当容易的，我必须这样做。
This.
这个。
And then jump, jump, jump, jump every time.
然后每次跳，跳，跳，跳。
Harder.
更难。
Not good.
不好。
Not good for my knees.
对我的膝盖不好。
Not good for my score.
对我的分数不好。
So I don't want to do this.
所以我不想这样做。
I want to have an intermediate state so I can say,
我想要一个中间状态，所以我可以说，
I start here and then I get back here.
我从这里开始，然后回到这里。
Then I do this.
那我做
Then I get back here.
然后我回到这里。
Then I go here.
那我去这里
And then I go back here.
然后我回到这里。
And then go back.
然后回去。
Do guys see how this works?
大家知道这是怎么回事吗？
AUDIENCE: You could also rock back and forth
听众：您也可以来回摇摆
to because they don't require both feet to be on the ground
因为他们不需要两只脚都在地上
the entire time.
整个时间。
PROFESSOR: Rock back and forth.
教授：来回摇摆。
Hold that thought.
保持那个想法。
That might come in handy.
可能会派上用场。
Assuming we have enough time.
假设我们有足够的时间。
So, if we only do one move every time we see a note,
因此，如果我们每次看到音符时只走一动，
we're stuck with this.
我们被困住了。
In our to allow re-centering, we have
为了使我们能够重新居中，我们有
to add states between the notes.
在注释之间添加状态。
We need to add an intermediary state.
我们需要添加一个中间状态。
And you can either think about it, or take my word for it,
您可以考虑一下，也可以相信我，
but if you represent the notes using the trick that I said
但是如果您使用我说的技巧来代表笔记
above, and you want to represent centering, then all you need
以上，而您想代表居中，那么您所需要的就是
is one extra state.
是一种额外的状态。
So one extra move between every two states.
因此，每两个状态之间要多移动一个。
Between two notes.
在两个音符之间。
And that's enough.
这就足够了。
Because that one extra state allows you to center.
因为那一种额外的状态使您能够居中。
And it allows you to do pretty much everything a beginner
它使您几乎可以做初学者的所有事情
like me would know how to do.
像我一样会怎么做。
AUDIENCE: So you only need one extra state between each note?
听众：那么您在每个音符之间只需要一个额外的状态？
PROFESSOR: Yep.
教授：是的。
That is the inside.
那就是里面。
That is where I'm thinking, right?
那是我在想的地方，对吧？
So I have to do both this trick, to see
所以我必须同时做这把戏
that I don't need an infinite number of steps.
我不需要无数个步骤。
And come up with the need for centering
并提出居中的需求
to see why I need one intermediate step.
了解为什么我需要一个中间步骤。
By the way, does anyone know what's
顺便说一句，有人知道什么吗
the right way of doing that?
正确的做法吗？
What's the right way of doing this move?
采取此举的正确方法是什么？
You said, rock back and forth.
你说，来回晃动。
So I wouldn't rock back and forth in this case, right?
因此，在这种情况下，我不会来回摇摆，对吗？
Because that wouldn't be helpful.
因为那不会有帮助。
How would I rock?
我会如何摇滚？
AUDIENCE: Well, you hold down one
听众：嗯，你按住一个
and then you go to the other one.
然后您转到另一个。
PROFESSOR: Yeah, so rock left and right.
教授：是的，所以左右摇摆。
OK.
好。
AUDIENCE: I said back and forth, I meant rocking--
听众：我来回说，我的意思是摇摆-
PROFESSOR: Sorry.
教授：对不起。
I thought back, forth.
我回想了一下。
So, the optimal way of doing this
所以，这样做的最佳方法
is left, right, left, right, left, right.
是左，右，左，右，左，右。
So what am I doing?
那我在做什么呢？
AUDIENCE: You have another move.
听众：您还有另外一个举动。
You have, like, one state for your foot where
您的脚有一种状态
it's not touching the ground.
它没有触地。
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
It's an interesting, and important, distinction.
这是一个有趣且重要的区别。
So if I wanted to hit both of them, if I'm here,
所以如果我想打他们两个，如果我在这里，
and I need to hit both of them, I need to hit them.
我需要打他们两个，我需要打他们。
If I only need to hit one of them, if I'm here,
如果我只需要打一个，如果我在这里，
I can hit it like this.
我可以这样打
If I'm here, though, and I want to hit it,
如果我在这里，但我想打它，
I have to lift myself up.
我必须振作起来。
So the difference is whether I'm like this.
所以区别在于我是否喜欢这个。
Or like this.
或者像这样。
Where is my weight?
我的体重在哪里？
So if I want to allow for these moves,
因此，如果我想允许这些举动，
if I want to go past the stage of very beginner,
如果我想超越初学者的阶段，
aside from keeping track of where my feet are,
除了跟踪我的脚在哪里，
I have to keep track of whether my weight is on my left foot
我必须跟踪自己的体重是否在左脚上
or on my right foot.
或在我的右脚。
So, I would actually have l, r, and W,
因此，我实际上会有l，r和W，
where W is either l or r.
其中W是l或r。
AUDIENCE: So your state now has what you're currently
听众：所以您的州现在拥有您目前的状态
putting more weight on.
加大重量。
PROFESSOR: And where each of the feet are.
教授：每只脚都在哪里。
AUDIENCE: Yeah.
听众：是的。
Where your two feet are.
你的两只脚在哪里。
And then also, the song difficulty.
然后还有歌曲的难度
So it's everything in your state, right?
一切都在您的状态中，对吧？
PROFESSOR: Ah, yes.
教授：是的。
I didn't think about it.
我没有考虑。
I was just talking about foot position.
我只是在谈论脚的位置。
But we need to get back to the state thing.
但是我们需要回到状态。
So that's a good point.
这是一个好点。
So before we get to that, how many feet positions do we have?
那么在我们做到这一点之前，我们要先坐几英尺？
If we don't include where do I have my weight,
如果我们不包括我的体重，
how many possible positions for both of my feet do I have?
我的双脚有几个可能的位置？
So I have two feet.
所以我有两只脚。
Each of them can be in any of these five squares, right?
每个人都可以在这五个正方形中的任何一个中，对吗？
So how many total positions?
那么总职位数是多少？
AUDIENCE: 5 choose 2.
受众群体：5选择2。
Using 2.
使用2。
PROFESSOR: So I can do this.
教授：所以我可以这样做。
AUDIENCE: Sure.
听众：好的。
Why not?
为什么不？
PROFESSOR: Well, if I have 5 choose 2, then you--
教授：好吧，如果我有5个选择2，那么您-
AUDIENCE: Oh, then that doesn't quite work.
听众：哦，那还行不通。
PROFESSOR: Yeah.
教授：是的。
AUDIENCE: Yeah, no.
听众：是的，不。
PROFESSOR: So flip.
教授：那么翻转。
AUDIENCE: Times 2.
观众：次2。
PROFESSOR: Yeah.
教授：是的。
So you have two feet.
所以你有两只脚。
Each foot, five possibilities.
每只脚有五种可能性。
Now, what if we have weight?
现在，如果我们有体重怎么办？
If we are tracking on where I keep my weight.
如果我们要跟踪我在哪里保持体重。
How many possible positions?
有多少个职位？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE]?
听众：[听不清]？
Oh no, because there's only two.
哦，不，因为只有两个。
PROFESSOR: So, for each of these,
教授：因此，对于每个
there's two possibilities now.
现在有两种可能性。
So 50.
50。
AUDIENCE: You also have to be so your weight is like this.
听众：您也必须如此，这样才能保持体重。
PROFESSOR: In the middle?
教授：在中间吗？
AUDIENCE: Yeah.
听众：是的。
PROFESSOR: You can.
教授：可以。
Based on that what I've been reading, you never want to.
基于我一直在阅读的内容，您永远不会想要。
Because if you're weight is in the middle,
因为如果您的体重在中间，
then you're extending a lot of effort to move either foot.
那么您将花费很多精力来移动任一只脚。
So you always want to have your weight somewhere.
因此，您始终希望将体重放在某个地方。
So that, at least for one of your feet,
因此，至少对于您的一只脚，
it's easy to move it.
移动起来很容易。
AUDIENCE: Could it be the back?
听众：会回来吗？
PROFESSOR: If that's not true, then yeah.
教授：如果不是这样，那么是的。
We'd need to have a center.
我们需要一个中心。
Oh, so, like, whether I'm like this or like this?
哦，所以，就像我是这样还是这样？
AUDIENCE: Yeah.
听众：是的。
If you were, like, doing the same thing.
如果您喜欢做同样的事情。
Rocking back and forth.
来回摇摆。
PROFESSOR: So, if I have two feet,
教授：如果我有两只脚，
then this says my weight is on my left foot.
这说明我的体重在我的左脚上。
My weight is on my right foot.
我的体重在我的右脚上。
So l and r is which foot, not where on the board.
所以l和r是哪只脚，而不是木板上的位置。
AUDIENCE: So, did you not do center because it was optimal?
听众：那么，您不是因为最佳而没有进行居中吗？
PROFESSOR: Because I claim that, in an optimal strategy,
教授：因为我主张以最佳策略，
you wouldn't have it.
你不会有它。
But you don't have to take my word for it.
但是您不必相信我的话。
If you don't believe me, then you add center.
如果您不相信我，那么请添加中心。
And you just have more possibilities.
而且您还有更多的可能性。
And if it happens to not be an optimal thing,
如果碰巧不是最佳选择，
then the dynamic programming will ignore it.
那么动态编程将忽略它。
So how many positions do I have if I add center?
那么，如果添加中心，我将拥有几个职位？
So if I have left, center, right for each position.
因此，如果我在每个位置都左，中，右。
AUDIENCE: 75.
观众：75。
PROFESSOR: Cool.
教授：太好了。
Yes.
是。
AUDIENCE: So why is it 25?
观众：那为什么是25？
You wouldn't actually have both of your feet on the right.
实际上，您实际上不会双脚都在右边。
PROFESSOR: Why?
教授：为什么？
Maybe, well especially, for maximizing this one actually.
也许，尤其是为了最大限度地提高这一能力。
Especially for maximizing entertainment.
特别是为了最大程度地提高娱乐性。
Then it's way cooler to do this, right?
然后这样做比较酷，对吗？
[LAUGHTER]
[笑声]
You get the point.
你明白了。
AUDIENCE: --possible weight.
听众：-可能的体重。
Like combinations for like, where is
相似组合的相似之处在哪里
you should have your feet at one time.
你应该一次站起来。
Like, not necessarily what the game is asking you to do.
喜欢，不一定是游戏要你做什么。
PROFESSOR: Yeah.
教授：是的。
So this is where my feet are.
这就是我的脚所在。
The game will always ask something like this.
游戏总是会问这样的事情。
So the game won't always care about both of my feet.
所以游戏不会总是在乎我的双脚。
Sometimes it'll only care about one foot.
有时只关心一只脚。
So, yeah.
是的。
There are two different concepts, right?
有两个不同的概念，对吗？
There's the position of my feet.
这是我脚的位置。
And then there's the note on the screen.
然后屏幕上有笔记。
And my feet have to match the note on the screen.
而且我的脚必须与屏幕上的音符匹配。
And we'll have to capture that somehow.
而且，我们必须以某种方式捕获它。
So what's in a state?
那么状态如何？
What are my decisions?
我的决定是什么？
Come on, now.
快点
We should be in a good shape to know what my decisions are.
我们应该处于良好状态，以了解我的决定。
What do I decide every time?
我每次都决定什么？
AUDIENCE: What move to make?
听众：采取什么措施？
PROFESSOR: Yeah.
教授：是的。
How am I going to jump, right?
我怎么跳，对吗？
Where my feet are going to be in the new position.
我的脚将要处于新的位置。
So every time, I'm deciding what's the new foot position.
所以每次，我都在决定新的脚位置。
AUDIENCE: Aren't you also deciding weight position,
听众：您不是也在决定体重位置吗？
where you're going to hold to, right?
你要坚持的地方，对不对？
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
So when I say foot position, it's a cheat for everything.
因此，当我说脚步姿势时，一切都是骗人的。
So yeah.
是的。
Good observation.
好观察。
OK.
好。
What do I need to know, in order to make this decision?
我需要知道什么才能做出此决定？
OK.
好。
I would need to know where I was before
我需要知道我以前在哪里
if I want to compute the difficulties.
如果我想计算困难。
But aside from that-- what?
但是除此之外-什么？
AUDIENCE: Sir, it came up with this polynomial.
听众：主席先生，它提出了这个多项式。
PROFESSOR: All right.
教授：好的。
AUDIENCE: Is that a hint to what the run time of this will be?
听众：这是否暗示了它的运行时间？
PROFESSOR: It's not on purpose.
教授：这不是故意的。
But yes.
但是，是的。
So, yeah.
是的。
That makes sense.
那讲得通。
Probably not good.
可能不好。
I should probably not have my screen up without me
没有我，我可能不应该把屏幕关起来
looking at it.
看着它。
OK, so.
好吧
Back to decisions.
回到决定。
I think I want to know what's going to be on the screen
我想我想知道屏幕上会发生什么
when I land, right?
当我降落时，对不对？
Because if the screen says, yo, you need to go up and down.
因为如果屏幕上显示“哟”，那么您需要上下移动。
Then maybe I shouldn't do this, right?
那也许我不应该这样做，对吗？
That would not be good.
那不是很好。
So I need to know what the note is going to be when I land.
所以我需要知道降落时的音符会是什么。
Note.
注意。
AUDIENCE: Is that the same as the next?
听众：与下一个相同吗？
PROFESSOR: Yep.
教授：是的。
Next note.
下一个音符。
Yes.
是。
So the next note here on the screen.
因此屏幕上的下一个音符。
So, my position in this list, basically.
因此，基本上，我在这份名单中的位置。
AUDIENCE: So it's kind of like the knapsack problem, where
听众：这有点像背包问题，
it's like which thing we're considering picking up.
就像我们要考虑的事情。
But in this case, it's coming [INAUDIBLE].
但是在这种情况下，它即将[听不清]。
PROFESSOR: So it's close to knapsack.
教授：因此，它接近背包。
But the difference is, in knapsack, I
但是不同的是，在背包里，我
have to decide, do I choose this or do I ignore it.
必须决定，我选择这个还是忽略它。
So, if I'd be like, if I can only do a few things
所以，如果我愿意，我只能做几件事
and I want to maximize my score, then
我想最大化自己的分数，然后
maybe I would choose, all right.
也许我会选择，好的。
This is easy.
这很容易。
I'm going to do it.
我要去做
This is hard.
这很难。
Screw it.
算了。
This is easy.
这很容易。
I'm going to do it.
我要去做
So then my decisions are 0, 1.
所以我的决定是0，1。
Pick or not pick.
选择还是不选择。
In this case, every time my decision
在这种情况下，每次我的决定
is a new state of my feet.
是我脚下的一种新状态。
So it's not 0, 1.
因此它不是0、1。
AUDIENCE: OK.
听众：好的。
PROFESSOR: That's the difference.
教授：就是这样。
And then, because of that, the state
然后，因此，国家
is going to look different.
看起来会有所不同。
And the recursion's will look a bit different.
递归的看起来会有所不同。
OK.
好。
So I want to know the note that I'm landing at.
所以我想知道我要降落的音符。
I want to know the sum of-- well,
我想知道-嗯，
we'll see if I want to know the sum of difficulties
我们看看我是否想知道困难的总和
up to this point.
到这一点。
And I want to know one more thing, so.
我还想知道一件事。
If this is going to be my new state,
如果这将是我的新状态，
and I know what note I'm landing at, I'm making a decision.
而且我知道我要下注，我正在做决定。
The decision tells me where my feet are going to be.
这个决定告诉我我的脚在哪里。
Right?
对？
The move decides where my feet are going to be.
此举决定了我的脚在哪里。
What do I need to do?
我需要做什么？
What else do I need to know for my total solution?
我的总体解决方案还需要了解什么？
So what do I need to know to consider between decisions?
那么我需要知道哪些才能在决定之间进行考虑？
So say I'm considering the state of-- I'm at note two.
所以说我正在考虑状态–我在第二点。
Note two says, left right.
注意二说，从左到右。
And I'm considering of coming here
我正在考虑来这里
from note one, where my foot position was up down.
从注一看，我的脚的位置向下。
Or come here from note one, where
或者从注释一来这里
my foot position was left right.
我的脚的位置是左右。
I need to know where my foot position was,
我要知道脚的位置
to choose between these, right?
在这些之间选择，对不对？
If I don't know that, then I can't choose.
如果我不知道，那我就选择不了。
AUDIENCE: That's not from your state, though?
听众：那不是你的状态吗？
PROFESSOR: Not yet.
教授：还没有。
It's not here, so it's not part of my state.
它不在这里，所以这不是我的状态的一部分。
We've been talking about it a lot, but we didn't put it here.
我们一直在谈论它，但是我们没有把它放在这里。
So let's say that the state is going
假设国家正在发展
to have the note that I'm landing at.
有我要降落的音符。
And my foot position after landing.
和我着陆后的脚位置。
So, if I know that I'm going to land like this,
所以，如果我知道我要像这样降落，
then I know where I was here. l r.
然后我知道我在这里。拉河
Say, l r.
说，河。
I can compute the costs here, right?
我可以在这里计算成本，对不对？
This is delta of going from this to this.
这是从此到此的增量。
And this is the delta for going from this to this.
Can you see?
你知道吗？
Is that too small?
那太小了吗？
Delta wants to know where my feet were before.
三角洲想知道我的脚在哪里。
And where they're going to be now.
以及他们现在要去的地方。
So when I call it, I need to know where I was before.
因此，当我打电话给我时，我需要知道我以前在哪里。
And I need to know where I'm going to be now.
我需要知道我现在要去哪里。
So this should be part of my state.
所以这应该是我的状态的一部分。
So our decision says, what's my new position going to be?
所以我们的决定说，我的新职位是什么？
So when I make a move, I influence my new foot position.
因此，当我移动时，会影响我的新脚位置。
They're going to be in someplace.
他们将在某个地方。
And independently of that, the note-- the position here--
而且与此无关，该音符-此处的位置-
the position of the note, increases all the time, right?
音符的位置一直在增加，对吗？
Because time can only go forwards.
因为时间只能前进。
How are we going to account for these extra moves?
我们将如何考虑这些额外的举动？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE].
听众：[听不清]。
PROFESSOR: So, we said that between every two notes,
教授：所以，我们说在每两个音符之间，
we might want to make one extra move.
我们可能要多采取一些行动。
AUDIENCE: Like, a potential new note
听众：喜欢，一个潜在的新音符
in between your destination note?
在目的地注释之间？
PROFESSOR: Yep.
教授：是的。
AUDIENCE: And then just fill in the difficulties for that
听众：然后填写相关的困难
and see which ones--
看看哪个-
PROFESSOR: So, if I want to use the algorithm that I already
教授：所以，如果我想使用已经存在的算法
have, that compares my landing position to my note,
可以比较我的着陆位置和我的笔记，
to see whether I can go there or not, what note would
看看我是否可以去那里，那张纸条会
I want to put in that intermediate note?
我要插入中间注释吗？
So, you're basically saying that between every two notes,
因此，您基本上是说，在每两个音符之间，
I'm going to have one more note.
我还要再记一下。
And my feet can be wherever here.
我的脚可以在这里的任何地方。
AUDIENCE: Oh.
听众：哦。
I mean, you'll also have the edge originally
我的意思是，你本来也有优势
connecting them.
连接他们。
So, you'd have it going to the intermediate note,
因此，您可以将其转到中间音符，
but also from the destination.
而且从目的地出发
Yeah, like that.
是的，那样。
You'd have to--
您必须-
PROFESSOR: So, what note would I have here?
教授：那我在这里要注意些什么？
AUDIENCE: It makes you go to the center.
听众：它使您可以进入中心。
PROFESSOR: Do I have to be at the center?
教授：我必须在中心吗？
AUDIENCE: Well, you can be anywhere.
听众：好吧，你可以在任何地方。
PROFESSOR: Yeah.
教授：是的。
So I'm going to invent the blank note.
因此，我将发明空白便笺。
That's a big O. That means you can do whatever you want.
那是一个很大的O。这意味着您可以做任何您想做的事。
There are no constraints.
没有任何限制。
So that is just an intermediary state.
因此，这只是一个中介状态。
So then I'm going to take this input,
因此，我将接受此输入，
and I'm going to add these blank notes here.
我将在此处添加这些空白便笺。
And these map to adding notes in the graph.
这些映射到图中添加注释。
AUDIENCE: Well, then, when you just
听众：那么，当你
run through your difficulty function between each two notes
在每两个音符之间运行难度函数
and see if, for all the potential moves, which
并查看所有潜在移动是否
one minimizes that path.
一个使路径最小化。
PROFESSOR: Yep.
教授：是的。
So basically, I'm assuming I don't need this.
所以基本上，我假设我不需要这个。
I'm assuming that.
我以为是。
This is going to be where there's
这将是那里
at least one choice where this is going
至少要这样做的一个选择
to have the same cost as a direct note.
具有与直接记录相同的费用。
And then I'm going to say that instead
然后我要说的是
of having more complex shapes in the graph,
在图形中具有更复杂的形状
I'm going to insert extra moves here.
我将在此处插入其他动作。
AUDIENCE: OK.
听众：好的。
I would think that, if you have an intermediate move that
我认为，如果您采取中间措施，
might be less expensive, you should, like, just
可能会便宜一些，您应该只是
hop to that new position than to have
跳到那个新位置而不是拥有
an intermediate move, right?
中间动作吧？
PROFESSOR: Yeah.
教授：是的。
And I'm going to assume that either that's not the case,
我将假设不是这样，
or that I can always find an intermediate move that
或我总能找到一个中间步骤
makes my life better.
使我的生活变得更好。
AUDIENCE: Every case?
听众：每种情况？
PROFESSOR: Yeah.
教授：是的。
PROFESSOR: These results do work.
教授：这些结果确实有用。
You'll have to take my word for it that this works.
您必须接受我的保证。
And this makes your dynamic programming easy.
这使动态编程变得容易。
And it makes your graph building easy.
它使您的图形构建变得容易。
So the advantage of this is you're changing the input.
因此，这样做的好处是您可以更改输入。
And then, when you're building your graph
然后，当您建立图表时
or when you're doing the DP, you only
或在执行DP时，仅
worry about an input that looks like this.
担心输入看起来像这样。
You don't care about any intermediate stuff.
您不在乎任何中间的东西。
You have notes, and you have to transition between the notes.
您有注释，并且必须在注释之间转换。
Period.
期。
So we reduce the complexity of the problem.
因此，我们降低了问题的复杂性。
So whenever you can get away with that, it's really nice.
因此，只要您能摆脱它，那真的很好。
We can do that for centering.
我们可以做到居中。
We might not be able to do it for other more complicated
我们可能无法完成其他更复杂的操作
stuff.
东西。
OK.
好。
So, we sort of know what we want in a state.
因此，我们有点知道某种状态下的需求。
Now we want to build a graph, so that the path
现在我们要建立一个图，这样路径
from some source to some destination
从某个来源到某个目的地
has a cost that's equivalent to the sum of these difficulties.
所付出的代价等于这些困难的总和。
Right?
对？
Because then I can run the shortest path.
因为这样我才能走最短的路。
And my solution will be right there.
我的解决方案就在那里。
I know.
我知道。
You guys seem awfully sad.
你们似乎很难过。
Do you want to take a break and play for a little bit more?
您想休息一下再玩吗？
Yes?
是？
How many people want to play, instead of.
想玩多少人，而不是。
You don't have to play yourself.
您不必扮演自己。
You can just rest for these two or three minutes.
您可以休息两三分钟。
And you can watch someone else play.
您可以看别人玩。
And get more intuition about how you're supposed to play.
并获得更多关于您应该如何比赛的直觉。
OK.
好。
So one person wants to take a break.
所以一个人想休息一下。
Everyone else wants to keep going?
其他人都想继续吗？
Or are you guys passed out already?
还是你们已经昏倒了？
AUDIENCE: Can we get out early?
听众：我们可以早点离开吗？
PROFESSOR: Sort of.
教授：有点。
Yeah.
是的
You'll get out three minutes early,
你会提前三分钟出去
if we don't do another round.
如果我们不做另一轮。
So who wants to keep going?
那么谁愿意继续前进呢？
AUDIENCE: No.
听众：不。
Let's play.
让我们玩。
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
So who wants to keep going?
那么谁愿意继续前进呢？
You can only vote on one thing.
您只能对一件事投票。
Who wants to play?
谁想玩？
AUDIENCE: OK.
听众：好的。
AUDIENCE: Five.
听众：五。
AUDIENCE: Four.
听众：四。
AUDIENCE: Victor, go.
听众：维克多，走。
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
Who wants to go?
谁想去？
So we decided what we're going to have in notes.
因此，我们决定了笔记中将要包含的内容。
And we're going to build a graph, where
我们将建立一个图形
the notes are the states.
笔记是状态。
And the edges are the moves.
而边缘就是动作。
Right?
对？
So a note tells me, just like there, what note I'm at.
因此，有一个音符告诉我，就像在那儿一样。
Say I'm at note two.
说我在第二注。
And where my feet are on.
而我的脚在哪里。
So, left foot left.
所以，左脚离开。
Right foot right.
右脚右。
So, given a state, what outgoing edges do I build?
因此，给定状态，我要构建哪些输出边缘？
Where can I go to?
我可以去哪里？
So let's say I have a state that says I'm at note n
假设我有一个状态，说我在音符n
and my left foot is in some position.
我的左脚在某个位置。
My right foot is in some position.
我的右脚处于某个位置。
What are my outgoing edges from here?
我从这里出去的边缘是什么？
AUDIENCE: Is there an outgoing edge to every move?
听众：每一步都有外向的优势吗？
Because there's a point.
因为有一点。
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
Well, actually, the blank is a note, right?
好吧，实际上，空格是一个音符，对吗？
So if the next note, if note three's a blank,
因此，如果下一个音符，如果音符三为空白，
then the note is a blank.
那么便笺为空白。
And then I can have.
然后我可以拥有。
AUDIENCE: I guess, isn't the difficulty
听众：我想这不是难事
of the move dependent on what note that blank actually is?
此举取决于空白实际上是什么？
PROFESSOR: So, it doesn't depend on what the screen says.
教授：因此，这并不取决于屏幕上显示的内容。
It depends on where my feet are.
这取决于我的脚在哪里。
AUDIENCE: Oh, OK.
听众：哦，好。
I see.
我懂了。
PROFESSOR: So I have a number that
教授：所以我有一个数字
tells me what's on my screen.
告诉我屏幕上的内容。
This number is enough for me to know
这个数字足以让我知道
what's going to be on my screen from now on until forever.
从现在开始一直到永远在我的屏幕上显示什么。
Because I have the list ahead of time.
因为我事先有清单。
And then I have the position of my feet.
然后我有了脚的位置。
So these are both part of the state.
因此，这些都是国家的一部分。
So I have notes for all the notes.
所以我有所有笔记的笔记。
And all the positions of the feet.
以及脚的所有位置。
AUDIENCE: Right.
听众：对。
But the blank note is just one position of feet?
但是空白便笺只是脚的一个位置？
PROFESSOR: No.
教授：不。
AUDIENCE: Or, it's all positions.
听众：或者，所有职位。
PROFESSOR: Yeah.
教授：是的。
AUDIENCE: Isn't the difficulty dependent
听众：不依赖于难度
on what position your feet end up?
您的脚最终处于什么位置？
PROFESSOR: Yeah.
教授：是的。
So it's from where I start to where I land.
所以这是从我开始到登陆的地方。
So, if I decide to start from here, and go here,
所以，如果我决定从这里开始，然后去这里，
the difficulty of this move is-- so it doesn't depend on
此举的困难在于-因此它并不取决于
whether I have a blank there.
我那里是否有空白。
And this was OK.
没关系。
Or, if I had an up down, then I just missed the note.
或者，如果我情绪低落，那么我只是错过了笔记。
But the difficulty, the effort I'm expending, is the same.
但是困难，我正在付出的努力，是相同的。
AUDIENCE: OK.
听众：好的。
But if you start from that other move and go to a different
但是，如果您从其他步骤开始，然后转到其他位置
position, that's--
位置-
PROFESSOR: If I go from this to this,
教授：如果我从这个转到这个，
then that's a different difficulty.
那是另外一个困难。
AUDIENCE: But it still could be a blank note?
听众：但这还是空白吗？
PROFESSOR: Yeah.
教授：是的。
So, a blank note will let me go wherever I want.
因此，空白便笺可以让我随心所欲。
AUDIENCE: I see.
听众：我明白了。
But there are different kinds of blank notes, with different--
但是有不同种类的空白便笺，其中-
I guess I'm confused as to what--
我想我对什么感到困惑-
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
So let's go through them again.
因此，让我们再次浏览它们。
AUDIENCE: Is it kind of like it's, like, spreading,
听众：是不是像传播，
so really when you have your source note,
所以当您有原始记录时，
it's actually connecting to every possible move.
它实际上与所有可能的动作都息息相关。
And every possible move is connecting to your next--
而且所有可能的举措都在连接您的下一个-
so it's kind of like a diamond shaped thing?
所以有点像菱形的东西？
PROFESSOR: Not quite.
教授：不完全是。
Not quite.
不完全的。
So, let's go through the notes again.
因此，让我们再次浏览笔记。
And then let's go through that.
然后让我们来看一下。
So the source move will be connected to some notes.
因此，源动作将与某些音符相关。
And then those notes will be connected to other notes.
然后这些笔记将被连接到其他笔记。
And it looks more like you have a big, outgoing degree.
而且看起来您的学历很高。
Then you have a big network.
然后，您将拥有一个庞大的网络。
Then the big, incoming degree.
然后是大的传入度。
It looks like a messed up sorting network.
它看起来像一个混乱的分拣网络。
So, notes are constraints.
因此，注释是约束。
This accepts any possible feet combination, right?
这接受任何可能的脚组合，对吗？
So this accepts this.
因此，这接受了这一点。
AUDIENCE: Is the first combination
听众：是第一个组合
contained in that note?
该说明中包含？
In that blank note?
在那空白的笔记里？
PROFESSOR: No.
教授：不。
The blank is a constraint.
空白是一个约束。
So, if I have a note that looks like this, then
所以，如果我有一个像这样的笔记，
if one of my feet is here and the other one is in the center,
如果我的一只脚在这里，另一只脚在中间，
then that's fine.
那很好
The constraint is met.
满足约束。
If one of my feet is up and the other one is down,
如果我的一只脚举起而另一只脚举起，
then the constraint is met.
然后满足约束。
AUDIENCE: But the edge running into that blank note,
听众：但是边缘碰到了空白的钞票，
depending on how your feet land, is different difficulty.
根据脚的着陆方式，难度有所不同。
Is that right?
那正确吗？
PROFESSOR: Yep.
教授：是的。
But when I compute the edge width,
但是当我计算边缘宽度时
I need to know where I'm landing exactly.
我需要确切地知道我要降落在哪里。
Not just where the note is because the note might
不仅是笔记所在的地方，因为笔记可能
admit multiple positions.
接受多个职位。
AUDIENCE: I see.
听众：我明白了。
PROFESSOR: So this guy admits all positions.
教授：所以这个人承认所有职位。
AUDIENCE: OK.
听众：好的。
PROFESSOR: This guy admits some positions, right?
教授：这个人承认一些职位，对吗？
These are l r, l r.
这些是lr，l r。
If I have up down, how many feet positions does it admit?
如果我仰卧起坐，它可以容纳多少脚？
AUDIENCE: Just one.
听众：一个。
PROFESSOR: Not great.
教授：不好。
AUDIENCE: No.
听众：不。
PROFESSOR: How many?
教授：多少？
AUDIENCE: As an intermediate?
听众：作为中间人？
PROFESSOR: If it's up down, then it's on the screen.
教授：如果它向下，则它在屏幕上。
My intermediates are all blank.
我的中间体都是空白的。
AUDIENCE: Oh, oh.
听众：哦，哦。
I thought you were saying start with that.
我以为你是从那开始。
PROFESSOR: So up down.
教授：那么下来。
If you see up down on the screen,
如果您在屏幕上向上看，
how many feet positions?
多少脚位置？
AUDIENCE: Left to right what it could have.
听众：从左到右可能会有什么。
PROFESSOR: Yep.
教授：是的。
So, if the screen says up down, the only two ways
因此，如果屏幕上下显示，只有两种方法
I can do that is this.
我可以做到的就是这个。
Or this.
或这个。
Right?
对？
So, two positions.
因此，有两个职位。
AUDIENCE: I see.
听众：我明白了。
AUDIENCE: Well, I mean, but you could have intermediate
听众：好吧，我是说，但是你可以有中级
where you step in the first one, then back.
首先进入第一个位置，然后返回。
PROFESSOR: But I don't care because I've
教授：但是我不在乎，因为我已经
added these blank notes.
添加了这些空白便笺。
And they take care of my intermediates for me.
他们为我照顾了我的中间体。
AUDIENCE: But so, we're saying where
听众：但是，我们说的是
the feet land aren't part of the note.
脚的着地不属于音符的一部分。
PROFESSOR: Nope.
教授：不。
They're just states.
他们只是国家。
So they're a decision I'm making.
因此，这是我的决定。
AUDIENCE: So, do we have the multiple-- no,
听众：那么，我们是否有倍数-不，
we don't because they're not part of the--
我们不是因为它们不属于-
PROFESSOR: For each note position here,
教授：对于这里的每个音符位置，
for every position in the screen thing,
屏幕上每个位置的东西
I have multiple feet positions that I could be in.
我可能处于多个脚位置。
AUDIENCE: Right.
听众：对。
Right.
对。
But then, are there multiple moves to get to those?
但是，要实现这些目标，是否有多种举措？
PROFESSOR: Yep.
教授：是的。
AUDIENCE: OK.
听众：好的。
So there's multiple moves connecting each.
因此，有很多动作相互关联。
PROFESSOR: Yeah.
教授：是的。
So for example, if I want to get to l r, up down here,
例如，如果我想去lr，在这里
I can go from l r, up down in the blank.
我可以从lr到空白处。
Or, I could have l r be like this.
或者，我可能会像这样。
And then transition.
然后过渡。
So I can have a lot of possible foot positions
所以我可以有很多可能的脚位
that I'm transitioning from in order to get here.
我要从这里过渡到这里。
AUDIENCE: But those aren't actually
听众：但是这些实际上并不是
separate notes on the graph.
图上的单独注释。
PROFESSOR: They are.
教授：是的。
They have to be.
他们必须是。
So these all have to be separate notes.
因此，这些都必须单独注释。
Because the edges are going to have separate weights.
因为边缘将具有不同的权重。
Right?
对？
This edge is going to have one weight.
该边缘将具有一个重量。
This edge is going to have another weight.
这条边缘将有另一个分量。
AUDIENCE: OK.
听众：好的。
That's what I thought.
那正是我所想。
But then you said there was only one blank.
但是随后您说只有一个空白。
Don't there have to be multiple blank notes for every foot
每只脚不必有多个空白便笺
thing.
事情。
If you're approaching a note from different--
如果您要使用的音符不同，
PROFESSOR: So, I'm not sure what you're asking.
教授：所以，我不确定您要问什么。
So, if you want to care about centering,
因此，如果您想关心居中，
if you want to have intermediate moves,
如果您想进行一些中间动作，
you need one blank note between every real note.
您需要在每个真实音符之间添加一个空白音符。
So that you're allowed to make one intermediate move between.
这样您就可以在两者之间进行一个中间的移动。
AUDIENCE: Right.
听众：对。
I get that that's talking about the on the screen.
我知道那是关于屏幕上的内容。
PROFESSOR: Yeah.
教授：是的。
That's the screen.
那是屏幕。
AUDIENCE: That's the screen.
听众：那是屏幕。
PROFESSOR: Yep.
教授：是的。
AUDIENCE: OK.
听众：好的。
So, that's not the graph, though.
所以，那不是图形。
Here, we're talking about the screen on the graph.
在这里，我们正在谈论图形上的屏幕。
PROFESSOR: Here, we're talking about the graph.
教授：在这里，我们谈论的是图表。
So two tells me that the screen is at note two.
所以两个告诉我屏幕在注释二。
Whatever that happens to be.
无论发生什么。
And my feet are in this position.
我的脚处于这个位置。
OK.
好。
So that's very important.
所以这很重要。
Thanks for asking because that's very important.
感谢您提出要求，因为这非常重要。
So, a state has the note that I'm landing at.
因此，一个州有我要降落的音符。
So, where the screen is.
因此，屏幕在哪里。
And where my feet are.
而且我的脚在哪里。
AUDIENCE: OK.
听众：好的。
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
AUDIENCE: The state corresponds to the nodes that you're on.
听众：状态对应于您所在的节点。
PROFESSOR: A note.
教授：注意。
A note is a state.
音符是一种状态。
So, a note is a state.
因此，注释是一种状态。
And a move goes between two states.
并且在两个状态之间移动。
This is how we represent all the graph problems.
这就是我们表示所有图形问题的方式。
OK.
好。
AUDIENCE: So, you need multiple blank.
听众：因此，您需要多个空白。
PROFESSOR: Yeah.
教授：是的。
So here, I'm just drawing one example.
所以在这里，我仅举一个例子。
Yeah.
是的
So for example, here I would need-- sorry.
例如，在这里我需要-抱歉。
Oh, OK.
哦好的。
I get your confusion now.
我现在让你感到困惑。
So, yeah.
是的。
This would be one move.
这将是一招。
This would be another move.
这将是另一步。
AUDIENCE: That's all for a single thing on the screen.
听众：屏幕上的所有东西都是这样。
PROFESSOR: Yep.
教授：是的。
AUDIENCE: OK.
听众：好的。
OK.
好。
That makes sense.
那讲得通。
AUDIENCE: So the next note would have a really large end
听众：所以下一个音符的结局很大
degree, right?
学位，对不对？
I guess they always have--
我想他们总是-
AUDIENCE: Well, no.
听众：好吧，不。
It'd have lots of--
它会有很多
PROFESSOR: So, this note has a huge out degree.
教授：因此，此笔记的程度很高。
AUDIENCE: Yeah.
听众：是的。
But I'm saying the ones that all those intermediates connect to.
但我是说所有这些中间物都连接到的那些。
PROFESSOR: Yeah.
教授：是的。
AUDIENCE: So, then, they would connect
听众：那么，他们会联系
with some note that have, like, really large degree.
带有很大程度的音符
PROFESSOR: Yep.
教授：是的。
AUDIENCE: But there's two of them after that, right?
听众：但是那之后有两个，对吧？
Because there would be two different--
因为会有两个不同的地方-
PROFESSOR: So, what's next?
教授：那接下来呢？
Next, is position, hmm.
接下来是位置，嗯。
How did U number them?
你是怎么给他们编号的？
I guess, crap.
我猜，胡扯。
No.
没有。
It's not going to match that, so.
所以不会匹配的。
Whatever we do, it's not going to match that.
无论我们做什么，都无法做到这一点。
Say the next note, 4, is just an up.
再说下一个音符4，就好了。
4 is up down.
4是向下。
And then I have two notes for it, right?
然后我有两个注释，对不对？
Wild One note, l r.
狂野一音，l r。
So this is note 4.
这就是注释4。
That happens to be up down.
那恰好是下跌。
And then I have this.
然后我有这个。
And every one of these connects to every one of these.
这些中的每一个都连接到其中的每一个。
AUDIENCE: If the next move is up down,
听众：如果下一步走高，
how can notes have down up?
纸币如何下降？
Oh, because you can switch the feet.
哦，因为您可以换脚。
PROFESSOR: Yep.
教授：是的。
AUDIENCE: Oh.
听众：哦。
PROFESSOR: Yeah.
教授：是的。
So, I aimed to ask you guys, how am I going to draw the edges?
所以，我打算问你们，我要如何画边缘？
But you guys made me do it with questions.
但是你们让我提出了问题。
So, suppose I met note n, l, r.
因此，假设我遇到了注n，l，r。
What edges do I draw going out of it?
我要画出什么边缘？
So, note n, left foot at some position.
因此，请注意n，左脚在某个位置。
Right foot at some position.
右脚在某个位置。
What are my outgoing edges?
我的外向优势是什么？
AUDIENCE: This is a note on the screen.
听众：这是屏幕上的注释。
Or--
要么 -
PROFESSOR: In the graph.
教授：在图中。
AUDIENCE: --the new one or intermediate one?
听众：-新的还是中间的？
PROFESSOR: Doesn't matter.
教授：没关系。
So, intermediate notes have a note blank.
因此，中级注释的注释为空白。
AUDIENCE: That's just everything.
听众：仅此而已。
PROFESSOR: It doesn't matter.
教授：没关系。
Yeah, we're looking at all of them at the same time.
是的，我们要同时查看所有这些。
AUDIENCE: Wait, so you're asking what are--
听众：等等，所以您要问-
PROFESSOR: So, given this note, who am I connecting it to?
教授：那么，给了这篇笔记，我应该和谁联系？
Let's draw the outgoing edges.
让我们画出边缘。
So, if you're solving this as a graph problem,
因此，如果您将其作为图形问题解决，
you build the notes.
您建立笔记。
You draw the edges.
您绘制边缘。
You're on some algorithm.
您正在使用某种算法。
So let's draw the edges.
因此，让我们绘制边缘。
AUDIENCE: I think it depends if you're an intermediate note
听众：我认为这取决于您是否是中级音符
or not.
或不。
PROFESSOR: Nope.
教授：不。
So the note tells you what your constraints are.
因此，该注释告诉您您的约束是什么。
And that covers intermediate notes.
这涵盖了中级音符。
If you're note is a blank, then, well, there's no constraints.
如果您注意的是空白，那么没有任何限制。
If the note is not a blank, then there are constraints.
如果注释不是空白，则存在约束。
AUDIENCE: Oh, note.
听众：哦，注意。
I thought that was referring to the note, not the--
我以为那是指笔记，而不是-
PROFESSOR: No.
教授：不。
So this is a note.
因此，这是一个注释。
Maybe n is not good.
也许n不好。
Let's use i, instead, then.
那么，让我们使用i。
If n is hard.
如果n很难。
So, i is the position here, in this guy.
所以，我是这个人的职位。
Right?
对？
Say for example, i equals 1 here.
举例来说，我在这里等于1。
I equals 2 here.
我在这里等于2。
I equals 3 here.
我在这里等于3。
So and so forth.
等等。
And that doesn't match this, so.
那与这个不匹配，所以。
AUDIENCE: We're talking about note--
听众：我们正在谈论笔记-
PROFESSOR: Yep.
教授：是的。
AUDIENCE: --not--
听众：-不-
PROFESSOR: If one note is represented
教授：如果有一个音符
by these three numbers, right?
用这三个数字吧？
Each note has this tuple in it.
每个音符都有这个元组。
AUDIENCE: Then i is the note.
听众：那么我就是音符。
PROFESSOR: Yep.
教授：是的。
AUDIENCE: So i connects to i plus 1.
听众：所以我连接到我加1。
And then all possibilities known.
然后所有可能性都知道了。
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
So this connects to i plus 1.
所以这连接到我加1。
And then all possible destinations, right?
然后是所有可能的目的地，对不对？
So I'm going to say left.
所以我要说左。
This is after the jump.
这是跳跃之后。
So, left after the jump, and right after the jump.
因此，跳后左移，跳后右移。
And this is for all possible left after a jump,
这是跳跃后剩下的所有可能的东西，
right after the jump.
跳后
And lost a weight on this edge.
并失去了这一优势。
AUDIENCE: The way that it's from--
观众：来源-
AUDIENCE: l r to
听众：lr to
AUDIENCE: --l r to l r.
听众：--lr至l r。
AUDIENCE: l j-- l sub j r.
听众：l j-- l sub j r。
AUDIENCE: l r.
听众：l r。
PROFESSOR: So you want to say from l r to l j, r j.
教授：所以您想说从lr到lj，r j。
But what?
但是呢
AUDIENCE: Difficulty level?
听众：难度级别？
PROFESSOR: Yeah.
教授：是的。
Where is that?
哪里是？
AUDIENCE: Your difficulty function.
听众：您的难度函数。
PROFESSOR: Which is?
教授：那是什么？
AUDIENCE: Delta.
听众：三角洲。
PROFESSOR: Delta.
教授：达美航空。
So, yeah.
是的。
The weight is delta.
重量为增量。
I drew d.
我画了d。
Delta of these two foot positions.
这两个脚位置的Delta。
Almost.
几乎。
If I want to minimize the difficulty, then this is right.
如果我想最小化难度，那是对的。
If I want to maximize a score, then I
如果我想最大化分数，那么我
would have to add a minus sign.
将必须添加一个减号。
But if you're minimizing the difficulty,
但是，如果您将难度降到最低，
this is exactly the way because it maps the shortest path.
这正是方法，因为它映射了最短的路径。
Usually, in dynamic programming, things are maximized.
通常，在动态编程中，事物被最大化。
AUDIENCE: Wait, why would you add a minus if it's--
听众：等等，为什么要加上减号，如果-
PROFESSOR: So, if we're maximizing something,
教授：所以，如果我们要最大限度地发挥作用，
we have to flip-- we have to add a minus to the edge costs
我们必须翻转-我们必须在边缘成本上加上减号
because--
因为 -
AUDIENCE: Right.
听众：对。
PROFESSOR: Yeah.
教授：是的。
But this time we're minimizing something.
但是这次我们要最小化一些东西。
AUDIENCE: Oh.
听众：哦。
Right, right, right.
对，对，对。
PROFESSOR: I promised you that we'll maximize something
教授：我向你保证，我们会尽最大努力
all the time.
每时每刻。
Well, I guess I lied.
好吧，我想我撒了谎。
AUDIENCE: OK.
听众：好的。
Right, right, right.
对，对，对。
AUDIENCE: You don't want to maximize d.
听众：您不想最大化d。
Then you're dead.
那你就死定了
PROFESSOR: No.
教授：不。
You want to maximize show offs.
您想最大化炫耀。
So if we have the entertainment thing,
所以如果我们有娱乐的东西，
then that would be maximized.
那么那将被最大化。
And then you'd have minus.
然后你会减去。
AUDIENCE: Then you'd have everything you need.
听众：然后，您将拥有所需的一切。
PROFESSOR: Yep.
教授：是的。
AUDIENCE: OK.
听众：好的。
PROFESSOR: OK, so we're almost good.
教授：好的，我们差不多。
Source notes and destination notes.
源注释和目标注释。
AUDIENCE: Well, I guess source, we
观众：好吧，我想消息来源，我们
know that means start in the middle.
知道那意味着从中间开始。
Right?
对？
Like, you would start off with--
就像，你会开始-
PROFESSOR: What's the source?
教授：来源是什么？
You want to start at the first note, right?
您想从第一个音符开始，对吗？
AUDIENCE: Yeah.
听众：是的。
PROFESSOR: But in which position?
教授：但是在哪个位置？
AUDIENCE: Well, in the center, right?
听众：好吧，在中心，对吧？
I mean, the [INAUDIBLE] start.
我的意思是，[听不清]开始。
Or, I guess you could start--
或者，我想您可以开始-
AUDIENCE: Wherever you want.
听众：无论您在哪里。
AUDIENCE: Could you add a source note
听众：您能添加原始记录吗
going to a bunch of intermediate notes?
去一堆中级音符？
PROFESSOR: Yeah.
教授：是的。
Yeah.
是的
So what I'm going to do is I'm going to say there is a note 0.
因此，我要说的是音符0。
That let's me choose how I'm going to start.
那让我选择开始的方式。
AUDIENCE: Oh, it could be any position.
听众：哦，可能是任何位置。
It's like an intermediate note itself.
它本身就像一个中级音符。
PROFESSOR: Yep.
教授：是的。
So I'm going to have a note 0, with all possible foot
所以我要记下音符0，所有可能的支脚
positions.
职位。
And then this is going to be connected to a source,
然后将其连接到源，
by edges of weight 0.
按权重0的边。
So the intuition is that I get to choose my starting position,
因此，直觉是我可以选择自己的开始位置，
right?
对？
Starting position.
起始位置。
I see the first note.
我看到第一个音符。
I make a move.
我走了
So I want to be able to choose the starting position.
因此，我希望能够选择起始位置。
That's why I have all those notes.
这就是为什么我有所有这些笔记。
And then make a move to touch the first note.
然后移动以触摸第一个音符。
AUDIENCE: The starting position is also a note.
听众：起始位置也是一个注释。
PROFESSOR: Yep.
教授：是的。
Because, if the first note is here,
因为，如果第一个音符在这里，
I don't necessarily want to start like this
我不一定要这样开始
because maybe this is harder than this.
因为也许这比这难。
All right.
好吧。
What's the destination?
目的地是哪里？
AUDIENCE: The last note.
听众：最后一点。
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
So, all the notes that are at note n, and have any position,
因此，所有在音符n上并处于任意位置的音符
would be connected to a destination note,
将连接到目的地记录，
using an edge of weight 0.
使用权重为0的边。
Or I can consider them as destinations.
或者我可以将它们视为目的地。
And then choose the destination that has the shortest path.
然后选择路径最短的目的地。
AUDIENCE: Oh, I see.
听众：哦，我知道了。
The final destination is going to be, like, two notes.
最终目的地将是两个音符。
Right?
对？
It's going to be that last position, and then--
这将是最后一个位置，然后-
PROFESSOR: Or it might be more than two
教授：或者可能不止两个
if the note is just a simple note.
如果笔记只是一个简单的笔记。
Because that wouldn't constrain my feet too much.
因为那不会太大约束我的脚。
OK.
好。
And last, last question.
最后，最后一个问题。
Dijkstra or Bellman-Ford?
Dijkstra还是Bellman-Ford？
AUDIENCE: Bellman-Ford, because you
观众：贝尔曼·福特，因为你
have negative edges, negative weight,
负边，负重
as if you were going to maximize to death.
仿佛你要最大化死亡。
PROFESSOR: So, this is always going to be from 0 to 1.
教授：因此，它总是从0到1。
So I could possibly use Dijkstra.
所以我可能会使用Dijkstra。
The answer is neither.
答案都不是。
The answer is, we're building a DAG, so.
答案是，我们正在构建DAG。
AUDIENCE: Dijkstra.
听众：Dijkstra。
AUDIENCE: We don't use that.
听众：我们不使用它。
PROFESSOR: DAG, shortest path.
教授：DAG，最短路径。
Every time we have dynamic programming, DAG,
每次我们进行动态编程，DAG，
shortest path.
最短路径。
OK?
好？
AUDIENCE: Question.
听众：问题。
PROFESSOR: Yeah.
教授：是的。
Come on, last question.
来，最后一个问题。
You can't get away that easily.
您无法轻易摆脱。
OK, so.
好吧
Who wants to play?
谁想玩？